An election in South Korea even caused a political crisis. Is there
electoral fraud?  [Music]
Nationwalelections
will be heldacross
Kore.  On June 3, at the polling station of the first plan, some
voters were waiting for more than three hours, but at the end the staff came out and
said that the ballots were used up.  Oneelection
sever
Some people continue to wait, while others look at the hand darts and turn away.   As soon as it
happened in a country with seven years ago election democracy is the
reason for this one at one time of the national local elections,
50% of the country's polling stations stopped.
Voters human flesh surrounded the polling station and point center, the government deployed the Ministry of
Defense police, since
late to the seventh day, still many people are left searched in the meeting
.  For a while, the Internet
, because it says that the government is a black-clad election, there are also often said that foreign
forces have long entered the male Korean society, some even question the
police are not men at all.  In the end, is it a low-level
administrative mistake, or a premeditated election fraud?
[Cheer up]
Hello everyone who is abnormal, I am Ming.  After this happened
, we immediately asked in the community if you want to
do this mention, as a result, this machine is the most supported
time most of the questions of the discussion, is in which area the
accident
Why, there is not enough election in such a big election,
how do the blue government and even different officials respond to such a big farce
?  Finally and most importantly, is there
really a disadvantage behind this election?  [Music]
If you like this material, remember to leave a message and let our team know.
At the end of 2024, former President Shi, representing the Nationalist Party,
suddenly declared a national emergency and sent armed attempts to surround the meeting
.  It claims to have become a plate paradise, directly named China and
North Korea into the blue Korean society, and even has the ability to directly left and
right election results.  This statement has caused great controversy in South Korean society
, but whether you believe it at the time or not
, a year and a half later, it has once again become a
core topic in the blue society.  The Family Strict Action was eventually ruled a legacy constitution
.
After Li Ming came to power, the export of blue, and the stock market is now
significantly flipped.  Privately, the results are quite
good, but for a country that has just experienced the automatic
, the number is always a reference, the real
people's will have to be seen in the election.  Speaking of blue elections
, there are mainly three types of elections for presidential election members and this time
, the national local elections once every four years.  It is up to the
citizens to directly decide who sits on the ya Tiger Hill yeah and so on the
position of mayor of these major cities.  This election can be said
to be Li Ming's first national big mouth when he took office. The Common Democratic Party
certainly hopes to take advantage of the [music] momentum and extend the central advantage
to local governments.  The KMT will have to
rely on this election [music]
turmoil to prove to voters that it still has such a unified
democratic base.  Hey, we have put in all our efforts to mobilize. We need to
get good results this time.
[Music]
You wouldn't
have guessed that just when everyone's eyes were focused
on the election results, it was
not any political party that lost the whole election, but the people in charge of the election to
understand why there were not enough votes
.  Voidingthelocal
[Music]
Every election in South Korea goes to open early voting before the official polling day.
This time is no exception.
Before the official polling day on June 3, the election will suddenly
open polling stations for voters to vote in the
[music] battle on May 29 and 30.  During this time, voters can
vote across districts, at different polling stations. The practice is generally that
you first put your ID card, and then the system will
print a copy of the election belonging to your constituency on the spot.  But
this rule will be different on official polling day.
Voters can only go back to their registered constituencies to vote.
Because of this, the law stipulates that it is mandatory for the Electoral Commission to
print all the required ballots for the day in advance.  Then distribute
to various polling stations the day before the vote to ensure that each ballot has as much as it is
, how much is distributed, how much is paid, all clear.
But the question comes, exactly how much to print to save the law
does not state, the election is just an internal paper quotation, it
is the number of Anger voters to print.  But in recent years, early
voting has become more and more common, right? There are a
large number of unused stupid ballots left in each election.  And it is these
people who have been rescued for a long time, being can only be used as a
tool for electoral disadvantages or vote removal.  So the elected council saw that the
early voting was a historical high of 23%, more than
10.4 million people lost
.  Well, this decision has its logic on the surface
, but there is one thing that the Electoral Commission seems to have not thought of.
For example, high turnout does not mean that the number of people on a representative polling day will automatically
decrease.  Neither
because this is the first election after the turmoil, the
political atmosphere is the most tense in recent years, the two parties are chatting into full
mobilization, the overall vote two desire is obviously higher than ever.
In this one context the reduction was the reverse decision, and in
hindsight the elections totaled
73% of the printed funds, and in the end the actual national turnout
was 63% [music].   It's
up to you, 73% of the electorate and 63% of the voters voted, which
should be enough to make a difference.  So what exactly happened on election day
?  Amassive
number ofvoters
acrossKoreahadtothe
pollsforthis
selectionyesterday
drivingvoterturnto
itshighestlevel
decades.Early on
June 3, polling stations across Korea opened on time
[music], everything was still normal, but by
about 2pm the chatroom atmosphere between the polling station staff and the Electoral Commission
began to stop
We only have 35 ballots left now. There is a long queue at the scene
. Can we raise more ballots?  What about after the middle head
?  The situation is getting [music] more and more serious,
the number of votes in the ministry is already exceeding the expectations of the
election first,
I used all the
Cang It turns out that
50 of the 14,300 polling stations in the country are
forced to stop voting with all the ballots in their hands
.  However,
this is the most serious in areas such as Hushan,
but does not account for more than one-third of the cases.  In fact,
some polling stations still have a whole lot, but according to the cold, the electoral administration
will be without a content [music] plan
.  As a result, the voters have their own way to use plastic bags to
hold the ballots. The voters who are waiting to take them to the outside are just
waiting. Some people waited for a few hours, and some people
waited until they gave up and turned around to leave.  And in order to protect, the election will
announce the impact of the vote cut this, on the on-site voting time know on 10
o'clock.  However this decision simply did nothing to appease the already deeply
disgruntled voters.  [Cheer up] The
crowd started, they shouted slogans, demanding to stop counting votes,
the election was invalid, some people still sang with dragons and phoenixes simply to
cover up [music] disadvantages, but just as the Seoul Election Commission was
preparing to put the vote counting center, this crowd of citizens acted
[music] escalation
demand
blocked
straight after the end, that is, the morning of June 5
lock, successfully locate the head ticket dealer to the point center.
Na Although it was shipped away, but this election turmoil, did
not subside because of this, but instead in the heart of the head
, set off a bigger storm of With
other areas finished what?  The result is a period of ruling
party Common Democratic Party this Daesang won the 16 mayoral elections
but the first because short votes dragged how to
other areas
Eventually the National Power Party's not subdivided electoral market Here
election results Chen settled, but the number of people
followed the vote dealers
Heike Park is one of the points in Seoul affairs  The
election is not the administration of the bill, but the
actual section of the citizens' right to vote, so that the growth election loses the most
fundamental legality, in the face of the previous social backlash, the official finally can
not stand [music] it.  seems to pass.
Supreme Court judge Mrs. Noh, who is the chairman of the Central Election Commission, publicly
announced the quotation.  Even the chief-elected conservatives who are not subdivided have
stated on television [music] that short votes have
violated citizens’ right to vote.   The
President is concerned, and also asked [music] it has failed to
ask the National Assembly to spread the investigation, until Monday, a large number of
people still refused to go, civil society organizations also claimed that the
number of people rallying has broken through 50,000 people, and according to the local police
informal stock this peak period also gathered more than
30,000 people.  It was at this point that a detail started to
seal the internet.
Why are you so angry?  Because some of the demonstrators found that most of the
votes who did not have enough votes were the
most in those areas.  This observation made some of the
protesters more sure of their judgment, making it
difficult to explain administrative errors. For many ladies
, this was no longer a mistake, but evidence of the suppression of opposing
voting rights.  So he concentrated on the votes of the National Measures Party
?  This is true, but does it mean that there is
still not enough information to judge refers to another
more extreme opinion.
He said that South Korea is a disc paradise, and China will encounter However, there are
also online media
refuted it.  But there is
another kind of statement about holding the jug, or the different statements in the whole rally
, in fact, are all conservative hand supporters
made up, is they themselves can not afford to lose, even black
play.  So whether this men's election controversy is a no disadvantage
, or just the masses amplified a
logisticproblem, now
put in front of everyone's eyes is the set has internal logic but lacks
complete evidence [music] According to the statement
more depends on how much you are willing to accept the mouth of the mouth
Give them a fair chance to vote.
This ball has left too many unsolved groups to this day.
What logic is the election based on to decide Indo
's votes?  How come the vote disaster area happens to be concentrated on the
opposition votes?  Well, none of these questions have an official
completeness yet, but there is one thing we can do first in the process of awaiting a case
, which is to judge ourselves by what we are using.  Well,
looking at a controversial incident, the easiest trap to fall into is that I
believe the statement, and I go looking for evidence to support that statement
.  The [music] theory has its own internal logic, pure error
theory, and there are also frameworks that can be self-contained, but self-is
not equal to the truth. The question is whether the facts now known are enough
to support a certain conclusion
.  Is the Election Commission targeted to reduce the elections in this batch of areas,
or is the vote in this batch of areas particularly high after the same reduction nationwide?
These two possibilities lead to very different
conclusions, and the current public consultation is not sufficient to distinguish between the
two.  In addition to the controversy over whether there are disadvantages What this incident is
exposing is a crisis more difficult than fraud, a
crisis of institutional trust.  In a democratic society, being disappointed with the government is a big deal.
Kick him out in the next election.  But when the citizen electoral system
itself does not trust this, a self-correction mechanism fails
.  And once anger comes out of the body, it tends to only explode in more
extreme ways in society [music].  Thank you so many
abnormal and accompany back to our episode, plus what
issues we explore after you?  You are welcome to join the home on the piano box and
become our member, so you can
ask us questions directly during the live broadcast like other directors,
respond to your questions from our program and participate
in the voting.  Think about it and you believe that this vote turmoil
is an extremely low-level mismanagement yeah, there really was an election
dance.  Finally if irritating normal objective
obstruct preparation [music] view it ia